Foster Brothers
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Family Papers, 1875-1973, Series 8:; (Box 10; 6 folders)
  Family papers consist of a small number of personal papers of Foster Brothers founders, John Roy and Stephen Bartlett Foster, and also of Helen Foster Osborne (John’s daughter). A letter from Edward Everett Hale, 1889, accepting an invitation addressed to Mr. Foster could have been intended for either Stephen or John Foster. Also included are a silhouette of John R. Foster cut by Doris Burdick, and his personal account book with some brief diary entries that pre-date the establishment of Foster Brothers by more than a decade. Of particular interest is Helen Foster Osborne’s 1973 reminiscence of having her portrait painted by William Paxton in 1923. Helen Foster Osborne’s correspondence with Ernest Donnelley, post-dating the closing of Foster Brothers, concerns the sale of printing plates and dies from the miniature reproduction business.
  - To Mr. Foster, Letter from Edward Everett Hale, 1889 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - John R. Foster, Account Book, 1875-1880 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - John R. Foster, Silhouette Cut by Doris Burdick, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Stephen B Foster, Will, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Helen Foster Osborne, Correspondence with Ernest Donnnelly, 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Helen Foster Osborne, Photograph of Portrait of her by William Paxton (with reminiscence), 1923, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 38)
- Photographs, circa 1880s-1918, Series 9:; (Box 10; 5 folders)
  Photographs are of the Foster brothers, John Roy and Stephen Bartlett Foster. One portrait of each is in a "Keepsake Frame," a popular item designed and manufactured by Foster Brothers. Other people appearing in photographs are employees, most of whom are unidentified. Also included are pictures of the Foster Brothers' first frame factory on Cambridge Street, picturing the exterior of the factory and the "fitting room."
  - People, Employees, 1896, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - People, Foster, John Roy, 1880s-circa 1914 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - People, Foster, Stephen Bartlett, circa 1880s-1890s, undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Places, Foster Brothers Factory, Cambridge St. (exterior and "fitting room"), 1890s-1918 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Places, John and Stephen Foster, Charles Street Apartment, undated (Box 10, Folder 43)